<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rstats on Crystal Lewis</title>
    <link>https://cghlewis.com/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rstats on Crystal Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cghlewis.com/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data cleaning for data sharing</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/data_clean_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/data_clean_01/</guid>
      <description>Through various conversations over the last several months, a recurring question I keep hearing is, what makes a clean dataset? What steps do we expect someone to take before handing off a dataset that is considered &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo;? And I will tell you right now, there is no standard answer for this question. Even within fields, within projects, or within teams, you will get different answers depending on who you talk to, their role in the research cycle, and their past experiences and/or training with data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four simple ways to integrate your data dictionary into your data cleaning process</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/dict_clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/dict_clean/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier blog post I argued that data dictionaries are one of the most important pieces of documentation you can keep for a project and I spoke about the four purposes of a data dictionary. One of those purposes being that they can be integrated in your data cleaning process. And when I say &amp;ldquo;integrated&amp;rdquo;, I mean that in both a non-literal sense (for example I can refer to my data dictionary for guidance as to what transformations my data might need), but I also mean it in a very literal sense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
