<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education research on Crystal Lewis</title>
    <link>https://cghlewis.com/tags/education-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education research on Crystal Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cghlewis.com/tags/education-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let it go: Effectively delegating tasks</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/delegate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/delegate/</guid>
      <description>So, exciting news! My book, Data Management in Large-Scale Education Research, was recently published! As the title indicates, the book is not necessarily about managing small projects run by one person (although many of the practices are still applicable), but rather about how to manage a project that is large enough to necessitate more help. The large projects I am referring to often involve data collected in the field, on a large number of participants, over several waves of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating unique participant study identifiers</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/participant_id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/participant_id/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a discussion with a colleague about assigning unique participant identifiers in their study. In that discussion I learned that my opinion on how researchers should assign identifiers happened to be very different from how this colleague was assigning identifiers. This discussion then prompted me to question my assumptions about how I manage data (which I appreciate)! :)
For several hours after this discussion I scoured the internet for any advice, research, or opinions on how participant identifiers should be assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
