<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tips on Crystal Lewis</title>
    <link>https://cghlewis.com/categories/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tips on Crystal Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cghlewis.com/categories/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bare Necessities of Data Management</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/project_beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/project_beginning/</guid>
      <description>This summer I&amp;rsquo;ve been consulting on some early phase education research projects. These are projects that have recently been funded and are going into their first year of data collection. The people I consult with have reached out because they really want to set up good data management practices early on, saving them from potentially having to clean up data disasters later on. Coming in as a consultant, rather than a full-time employee, I find that my role is really to narrow in on what are the core priorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire a data manager</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/hire_datamgr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/hire_datamgr/</guid>
      <description>If you were struck by lightning, would other people be able to access and understand your data? - Sarah Arena
Even with the growing open science movement, the expanding requirements for publicly sharing sharing federally funded data, and the ongoing news about data falsification motivating us to produce more accurate, documented, and reproducible data, many researchers are still not able to confidently say &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to this question.
One solution to this problem is to hire a data manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Synthesis of Data Management Issues</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/synthesis_data_mgmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/synthesis_data_mgmt/</guid>
      <description>Everyone who works with data has experienced data management difficulties. While it is a pain in the moment to work through those issues, it is refreshing to know that you are never alone. This is evident from the several meetups that have even been started just to commiserate around shared data mishap experiences. Take for instance the Second Annual Data Mishaps Night occurring next Thursday February 24th, or the Be Afraid, Be Very Afraid: Data Management Horror Stories and Lessons Learned sharing session occurring at the COS: Unconference next Friday, February 25th.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
