<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks &amp; Workshops on Crystal Lewis</title>
    <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks &amp; Workshops on Crystal Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cghlewis.com/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>R for the Rest of Us Podcast Guest</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/rforrest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/rforrest/</guid>
      <description>In this podcast episode, David and I discuss topics such as the importance of data management planning, what a data validation and data cleaning process looks like, as well as my thoughts on writing my book using Bookdown in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management in Large-Scale Education Research</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/cos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/cos/</guid>
      <description>In this webinar I discuss why I wrote the open access book, Data Management in Large-Scale Education Research, as well as share a few key takeaways from the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Your Freelance Career</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/freelance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/freelance/</guid>
      <description>Materials from a presentation given to a group of students and faculty in the University of Nebraska, Lincoln QQPM Seminar. In this presentation I provided background into how I got into freelance consulting, as well as tips for anyone looking to get into this type of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning for Data Sharing Using R</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/ncme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/ncme/</guid>
      <description>Materials from a half-day professional development workshop given at the 2024 NCME Annual Meeting. This workshop provided a foundational understanding of how to organize data for the purpose of data sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Common Data Management Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/alaska/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/alaska/</guid>
      <description>These are materials for a presentation given to the Alaska Region of Fish and Wildlife Service for Data Week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Medical Data in R</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/rmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/rmed/</guid>
      <description>Materials from a workshop given at the R/Medicine 2023 Conference. My co-presenters included Shannon Pileggi and Peter Higgins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Data Management Best Practices and Tools for NIH Compliance</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/cos_nih/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/cos_nih/</guid>
      <description>This webinar features a panel discussion on how research teams can implement best-practice data management, with particular emphasis on the NIH’s Data Management and Sharing Policy requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management Workflows for Education Research Studies</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/uhcl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/uhcl/</guid>
      <description>These are slides from a guest lecture presentation for a graduate research methods class at the UHCL. The talk was on how to create data management workflows for education research studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Common Data Management Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/sssp_ecf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/sssp_ecf/</guid>
      <description>These are materials for a presentation given to the Society for the Study of School Psychology Early Career Forum.
This same talk was also given to the University of Washington, SMART Center on 2022-11-09.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison of Packages to Generate Codebooks in R</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/rladies_nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/rladies_nyc/</guid>
      <description>These are materials for a 5 minute lightning talk I gave to R-Ladies NYC. The topic was comparing 4 R packages that can be used to create codebooks to document your data.
*Note: On 2022-12-12 I made a small update to the slides. I discovered that the codebookr::codebook() function did not create 2 of the summary statistics I originally thought it did. So the slides now reflect this finding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management in Large-Scale Ed Research</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/mpsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/mpsi/</guid>
      <description>These slides are from a series of talks on best practices in documentation, creating a style guide and collecting data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
