<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data management on Crystal Lewis</title>
    <link>https://cghlewis.com/categories/data-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data management on Crystal Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cghlewis.com/categories/data-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ten Common Data Management Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/sssp_ecf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/sssp_ecf/</guid>
      <description>These are materials for a presentation given to the Society for the Study of School Psychology Early Career Forum</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Curated Collection of Data Management Resources</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/data_mgmt_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/data_mgmt_resources/</guid>
      <description>Below are resources for those wanting to learn more about research data management. I have organized resources by type (papers, guides, slides, etc). There are MANY more resources than the ones listed below, but I have narrowed them down to those that I have found most helpful in understanding general best practices in data management and how to implement them into a research workflow.
Resources were last updated on 2022/10/11</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management in Large-Scale Education Research</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/projects/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/projects/book/</guid>
      <description>About the Book The modules and book are a compilation of lessons I have learned in my personal experiences as a data manager, knowledge collected from existing books, sites and blogs (many written by librarians or those involved in the open science movement), as well as advice and stories collected through interviews with other researchers who work with data. I cover best practices throughout the research data management life cycle that education researchers and research staff can implement into their workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling Functions</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/projects/data_wrangling_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/projects/data_wrangling_functions/</guid>
      <description>About the Wiki The Data Wrangling Functions Wiki is a reference resource that I have been developing for myself and others to refer to when cleaning education data (or any data) using R. It is a collection of functions that I have found helpful to use in my data wrangling process and can be referred to whenever you forget how to or are unsure how to perform a data task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Available R Codebook Packages</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/projects/codebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/projects/codebook/</guid>
      <description>Codebook Comparison I started this table as a way to compare existing r packages that assist in codebook creation. The criteria I am looking for include the following variable level metrics (specifically for working with haven::labelled() data):
Name Label Type Values (if categorical) Value labels (if categorical) NA values (Missing values: for example -99 and -98) NA labels (Missing value labels: for example -99 = No response, -98 = Unclear response) Total valid N Total missing N N per value (if categorical) % per value (if categorical) N per NA value (Missing value) % per NA value (Missing value) Range (if continuous) Mean (if continuous) A table of all packages I reviewed can be found here: https://cghlewis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management Overview</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/schoen_res/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/schoen_res/</guid>
      <description>The slides are from a 6 part workshop series given to the Schoen Research Team at Florida State University. Parts 1 &amp;amp; 2 cover best practices throughout the research data managment life cycle. Parts 3-6 cover an introduction to R and RStudio and data wrangling in the Tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Synthesis of Data Management Issues</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/blog/synthesis_data_mgmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/blog/synthesis_data_mgmt/</guid>
      <description>Everyone who works with data has experienced data management difficulties. While it is a pain in the moment to work through those issues, it is refreshing to know that you are never alone. This is evident from the several meetups that have even been started just to commiserate around shared data mishap experiences. Take for instance the Second Annual Data Mishaps Night occurring next Thursday February 24th, or the Be Afraid, Be Very Afraid: Data Management Horror Stories and Lessons Learned sharing session occurring at the COS: Unconference next Friday, February 25th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management in Large-Scale Ed Research</title>
      <link>https://cghlewis.com/talk/mpsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cghlewis.com/talk/mpsi/</guid>
      <description>These slides are from a series of talks on best practices in documentation, creating a style guide and collecting data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
